Dr. Pezhman Zarabadi-Poor, Ph.D.

COMPUTATIONAL MATERIALS SCIENTIST

Department of Chemistry, University of Bath, Bath, United Kingdom

Summary _

I am eager in benefiting from the synergy between my computational skills and experimental background to tackle challenging energy and environmental obstacles at the intersection of material and computational science. I have developed the experimental skills throughout my MSc and PhD studies while I have learned computational techniques after my PhD on my own interest and effort. Although I am able to conduct independent research projects, I thrive working as a team member and have proactively collaborated with researchers at different institutions around the world to complete various projects.

Education

University of Tehran Tehran, Iran

Ph.D. in Inorganic Chemistry

Oct. 2008 - May 2013

· Specialized on synthesis of carbon nanotubes (solvothermal) surface modification of mesoporous silicas

University of Tehran Tehran, Iran

M.Sc. in Inorganic Chemistry

Oct. 2006 - Sep. 2008

• Specialized on Synthesis and characterization of carbon nanotubes (CCVD method) and mesoporous silicas **Bu-Ali Sina University**

B.Sc. in Applied Chemistry Oct. 2002 - Sep. 2006

Hamedan, Iran

Qazvin, Iran

Got the chance to work in oil refinery as internship

National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents

Diploma Oct. 1997 - Sep. 2002

Work Experience _____

University of Bath

Bath, United Kingdom

Research Associate June 2020 - Current

• Research associate in CATMAT project

Central European Institute of Technology - Masaryk University

Brno, Czechia

MarieSkłodowska-Curie Postdoctoral Fellow Apr. 2017 - Apr. 2020

• Principal Investigator of COMPSTORE project

National Autonomous University of Mexico Mexico Mexico City, Mexico City, Mexico

DGAPA Postodoctoral Fellow

Mar. 2016 - Apr. 2017

Implementing the biogas upgrading project

Helmholtz - Center of Environmental Research (UFZ)

Leipzig, Germany

Research Stay Jul. 2010 - Sep. 2010

Wet peroxide oxidation of organic pollutants

Behineh Kala Gostar
Tehran, Iran

Techinal staff 2008 - 2012

• Installation and service of BEL gas adsorption instruments

Pars Pamchal Paint factory Qazvin, Iran

R & D Researcher

Jun. 2011 - Dec. 2013

Developing different types of water resistant paints

Arak Oil refinery

Arak, Iran

Undergraduate Internship Jun. 2011 - Dec. 2013

• Working in different parts of QC lab

Publications:

PRE-PRINTS AND IN-PROCESS:

- P. ZARABADI-POOR, B. J. MORGAN, AND M. S. ISLAM, *Accelerated Discovery of Next-Generation Cathode Materials for Li-ion Batteries*, **CATMAT**, In-Preparation
- P. Zarabadi-Poor, X. Wang, J. Bocarsly, J. Lim, L. Daniels, R. Chen, B. J. Morgan, C. Grey, M. Rosseinsky, and M. S. Islam, Designing, Synthesis, and Characterization of Novel Sulphide Cathode Materials, **CATMAT**, In-Preparation
- P. ZARABADI-POOR, N. BRYAN, B. J. MORGAN, AND M. S. ISLAM, Designing Li-rich Novel Sulphide Cathodes using Li intercalation, **CATMAT**, In-Preparation
- H. RICHARDS, P. ZARABADI-POOR, B. J. MORGAN, AND M. S. ISLAM, *In-Silico Exploration of Potential Next-Generation Cathodes for Li-ion Batteries*, **CATMAT**, In-Preparation
- S. P. Huber, E. Bosoni, M. Bercx, J. Bröder, A. Degomme, V. Dikan, K. Eimre, E. Flage-Larsen, A. Garcia, L. Genovese, D. Gresch, C. Johnston, G. Petretto, S. Poncé, G.-M. Rignanese, C. J. Sewell, B. Smit, V. Tseplyaev, M. Uhrin, D. Wortmann, A. V. Yakutovich, A. Zadoks, P. Zarabadi-Poor, B. Zhu, N. Marzari, and G. Pizzi, *Common workflows for computing material properties using different quantum engines*, 2021 arXiv Submitted
- P. Zarabadi-Poor, Screening and Detailed Atomistic Investigation of CoRE MOFs for Xenon Recovery from Exhaled Anesthetic Gas, In-Preparation
- 2021 P. ZARABADI-POOR, Helium Capture inside NMR Machine: An Alternative Solution for Helium Recovery, In-Preparation

PEER-REVIEWED:

- O. Jurček, R. Puttreddy, F. Topić, P. Jurček, P. Zarabadi-Poor, H. V. Schröder, R. Marek, and K. Rissanen, *Heads or tails?* sandwich-type metallocomplexes of hexakis (2, 3-di-o-methyl)- α -cyclodextrin, Crystal Growth & Design, (2020)
- P. Zarabadi-Poor and R. Marek, Metal-Organic Frameworks for Helium Recovery from Natural Gas via N_2/He Separation: A Computational Screening, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C, 123 (2019), pp. 3469–3475
- P. Zarabadi-Poor and R. Marek, Comment on "Database for CO_2 Separation Performances of MOFs Based on Computational Materials Screening", ACS applied materials & interfaces, 11 (2019), pp. 16261–16265
- S. Panter and P. Zarabadi-Poor, *Computational Exploration of IRMOFs for Xenon Separation from Air*, ACS Omega, 3 (2018), pp. 18535–18541
- P. Zarabadi-Poor and R. Marek, *In Silico Study of (Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Zn)-BTC Metal-Organic Frameworks for Recovering Xenon from Exhaled Anesthetic Gas*, ACS Sustainable Chemistry & Engineering, 6 (2018), pp. 15001–15006
- P. ZARABADI-POOR AND T. ROCHA-RINZA, A Detailed Atomistic Molecular Simulation Study on Adsorption-Based Separation of CO_2 Using a Porous Coordination Polymer, RSC advances, 8 (2018), pp. 14144–14151
- L. Hajiaghababaei, S. Abozari, A. Badiei, P. Zarabadi-Poor, S. Dehghan Abkenar, M. R. Ganjali, and G. Mohammadi Ziarani, Amino Ethyl-Functionalized SBA-15: A Promising Adsorbent for Anionic and Cationic Dyes Removal, Iranian Journal of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering (IJCCE), 36 (2017), pp. 97–108
- M. KARIMI, A. BADIEI, AND P. ZARABADI-POOR, *The Impact of Cadmium Loading In Fe/Alumina Catalysts and Synthesis Temperature on Carbon Nanotubes Growth by Chemical Vapor Deposition Method*, Journal of Sciences, Islamic Republic of Iran, 26 (2015), pp. 17–24
- A. Shahbazi, R. Gonzalez-Olmos, F.-D. Kopinke, P. Zarabadi-Poor, and A. Georgi, *Natural and Synthetic Zeolites in Adsorption/Oxidation Processes to Remove Surfactant Molecules from Water*, Separation and Purification Technology, 127 (2014), pp. 1–9
- P. Zarabadi-Poor and J. Barroso-Flores, Theoretical Assessment of the Selective Fluorescence Quenching of 1-amino-8-naphthol-3, 6-disulfonic acid (H-acid) Complexes with Zn^{2+} , Cd^{2+} , and Hg^{2+} : a DFT and TD-DFT Study, The Journal of Physical Chemistry A, 118 (2014), pp. 12178–12183
- P. Zarabadi-Poor, A. Badiei, A. A. Yousefi, and J. Barroso-Flores, *Selective Optical Sensing of Hg(II) in Aqueous Media by H-Acid/SBA-15: A Combined Experimental and Theoretical Study*, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C, 117 (2013), pp. 9281–9289
- P. Zarabadi-Poor, A. Badiei, and A. A. Yousefi, *Synthesis of Novel Carbon Nanostructures through Solvothermal Route*, Scientia Iranica, 20 (2013), pp. 2382–2385

- 2012 L. HAJIAGHABABAEI, A. BADIEI, M. SHOJAAN, M. GANJALI, G. ZIARANI, AND P. ZARABADI-POOR, A Novel Method for the Simple and Simultaneous Preconcentration of Pb^{2+} , Cu^{2+} and Zn^{2+} Ions with Aid of Diethylenetriamine Functionalized SBA-15 Nanoporous Silica Compound, International journal of environmental analytical chemistry, 92 (2012), pp. 1352-1364
- L. HAJIAGHABABAEI, S. KAZEMI, A. BADIEI, P. ZARABADI-POOR, M. R. GANJALI, AND G. M. ZIARANI, Using the Hydroxymethyl-2012 Modified Nanoporous Silica as a PVC Membrane Electrode Modifier to Determination of Lead Ions, Analytical and Bioanalytical Electrochemistry, 4 (2012), pp. 246-261
- 2011 G. MOHAMMADI ZIARANI, A. BADIEI, M. AZIZI, AND P. ZARABADI-POOR, Synthesis of 3,4-dihydropyrano [c] Chromene Derivatives $using \ Sulfonic \ Acid \ Functionalized \ Silica \ (SiO_2PrSO_3H), Iranian \ Journal \ of \ Chemistry \ and \ Chemical \ Engineering \ (IJCCE),$ 30 (2011), pp. 59-65
- 2011 P. ZARABADI-POOR, A. BADIEI, B. D. FAHLMAN, P. ARAB, AND G. MOHAMMADI ZIARANI, One-pot Synthesis of Ethanolamine-modified Mesoporous Silica, Industrial & Engineering Chemistry Research, 50 (2011), pp. 10036-10040
- 2011 P. ZARABADI-POOR AND A. BADIEI, Synthesis of Carbon Nanotubes using Metal-modified Nanoporous Silicas, Carbon Nanotubes-Growth and Applications, (2011), pp. 59-74
- 2010 P. ZARABADI-POOR, A. BADIEI, A. A. YOUSEFI, B. D. FAHLMAN, AND A. ABBASI, Catalytic Chemical Vapour Deposition of Carbon Nanotubes using Fe-doped Alumina Catalysts, Catalysis Today, 150 (2010), pp. 100-106
- 2009 P. HASHEMI, M. SHAMIZADEH, A. BADIEI, P. ZARABADI-POOR, A. R. GHIASVAND, AND A. YARAHMADI, Amino Ethyl-functionalized Nanoporous Silica as a Novel Fiber Coating for Solid-phase Microextraction, Analytica chimica acta, 646 (2009), pp. 1-5

Workshops and Trainings

AiiDA Hackathon Bologna, Italy

Developing Code Plugins and Robust Scientific Workflows Feb. 2020

MSSC2019 - CRYSTAL17 Workshop

London, UK Ab initio Modelling in Solid State Chemistry Sep. 2019

AiiDA Workshop Lausanne, Switzerland

Writing Reproducible Workflows with AiiDA May 2019

RASPA Workshop Delft, Netherlands

Molecular simulations for adsorption/diffusion in nanoporous materials and modeling of ionic liquids Jun. 2018

At the heart of MOF chemistry: Topology

Workshop on using TOPOSPRO Software Nov. 2018

Munich, Germany

CEITEC-MU, Brno, Czechia

Mar. 2016 - Apr. 2017

Leadership Course by hfp Brno, Czechia Professional Development for Young Scientists Course Nov. 2018

Funding_

Marie Skłodowska-Curie/SoMoPro COFUND

207,000.00 Euro - 36 months Apr. 2017 - Apr. 2020

Advanced Carbon@MOF Composites for Gas Storage and Separation

DGAPA Postdoctoral Fund UNAM, Mexico

· Computer Simulation of MOFs for Biogas Upgrading

360,000.00 MXN (20,000.00 USD)-12 month

Iranian Nanotechnology Innovation Council Tehran, Iran

Scholarship 2011

· Financial support of PhD thesis **Iranian Nanotechnology Innovation Council** Tehran, Iran

Scholarship 2008 • Financial support of MSc thesis

PEZHMAN ZARABADI-POOR · RÉSUMÉ SEPTEMBER 7, 2021 PAGE 3/4

Collaborations __

CURRENT:

Prof. Berend Smit and Dr. Daniele Ongari

EPFL, Switzerland

May 2019 - now

Topic: Noble Gas Separation

• Accelerating the High-throughput Screening by Developing Novel Pre-selection Descriptors

Prof. Christopher Wilmer

University of Pittsburgh, USA

Topic: Carbon Capture

2016 - now

• Investigation of CO_2 Adsorption on Thermal Conductivity of MOF-177 series

PAST:

Prof. Bradley Fahlman

Central Michigan University, USA

Topic: Nanomaterials Synthesis

2008 - 2010

· Synthesis and Characterization of CNTs and Funcionalized Mesoporous Silicas

Dr. Joaquin Barroso-Flores

UNAM, Mexico

Topic: Optical Sensors 2008 - 2010

• Computational Exploration of Fluorescence Quenching in Mercury Sensors

Technical Skills & Software ____

Programming Advanced: Python

Learning: C/C++, LaTex

Codes and Software RASPA, Zeo++, Gaussian, CP2K, AIMALL, LAMMPS, Chargemol, VASP, AiiDA, CRYSTAL17, pylAST, ORCA, LOBSTER

aiida-bjm Author: Collection of AiiDA Workchains for Cathode Material Discovery - CATMAT

aiida-sqs Author: AiiDA Plugin for Generation of SQS - CATMAT

aiida-nmr Author: AiiDA Workflows for Simulation of NMR Chemical Shifts in Cathode Materials - CATMAT

aiida-porousmaterials Author: AiiDA Plugin for PorousMaterials package

aiida-MatDis Author: Collection of AiiDA Workchains for Materials Discovery

aiida-orca
 aiida-raspa
 aiida-raspa
 Contributor: AiiDA plugin for RASPA package
 aiida-zeopp
 aiida-cp2k
 Contributor: AiiDA plugin for Zeo++ Package
 Contributor: AiiDA plugin for CP2K package
 Zeo++
 Contributor: Improved a feature in the code

Supervision and Scientific Consultancy _____

Hollie Richards

University of Bath, Bath, UK

In-Silico Design of Next-generation Cathode Materials

Noah Bryan University of Bath, Bath, UK

Last Year Bachelor Student Nov. 2020 - Apr. 2021

· Computational Investigation of Candidate Prototypes for Designing Next-Generation Cathode Materials

Sabrina Panter CEITEC-MU, Brno, Czechia

visiting DAAS-RISE BSc student

PhD Student

Aug. 2018 - Sep. 2018

Jan. 2019 - Current

Apr. 2021 - Current

• Xenon Recovery from Air using MOFs

Mahya Asgharian Marzabad CEITEC-MU, Brno, Czechia

Materials Chemistry PhD student

• Optimization of Synthesis Variables of Selected MOFs for Noble Gas Separation

SEPTEMBER 7, 2021 PEZHMAN ZARABADI-POOR · RÉSUMÉ PAGE 4/4